Curso Agentes IA Gratuito para Iniciantes 2025 | Do
Zero ao Agente IA
Transcribed by TurboScribe.ai. Go Unlimited to remove this message.
"Welcome to this 100% free Agent of Air course. In this course you will learn the basics about Agent of Air. So what is Agent of Air? Why is it so important? And how can you make money with Agent of Air? And most importantly, this course is 100% practical."
I'll take you by the hand and I'll teach you how you can create your first Agent of Air step by
"step. So without further ado, let's see the project that you will build with me during this course. So we're going to create an Agent of Air with Telegram."
"Telegram will be our front-end. So we could connect WhatsApp or Instagram. In this case, I"
connected Telegram because it's more practical and more didactic when it comes to explaining.
"So this is the flow that we're going to build from scratch step by step in the N8n, which is"
"the best tool for you to build your Agents. And here you will have the part of receiving messages, dealing with these messages, the Agent of Air itself and answering the messages. Our Agent of Air will be able to look at the events on the calendar."
"So, for example, here in my events, I can see that I have an Air training and I have an"
academy here. And our Agent will understand both text and audio. Look how cool and complete this project is.
"So let's test it here for you to understand. I'll say here, Hi, who are you? I can say here who"
you are. It will run our Agent.
"It will say, your virtual assistant is designed to help you visualize and organize events in your"
"agenda. Wow, that's cool. Let's test the audio now."
"Wow, that's cool. I wanted to know if I have any events for today. Do you know what events"
"I have for today? Let's see, it will run."
Now the audio part has run. It will run our Agent. Let's see if it will connect to the calendar
and will answer the events I have for today because I already integrated there.
"So look how cool, you have the following events for today. An AI training from 3 to 14 and"
"an academy from 6 to 19. If you need more details of the event, just let me know."
"So if I click here, I can even open it. In this case, I'm in the Telegram app, but it's already"
showing my two events for today. So this project is too cool.
I'm going to get you here from scratch for you to learn the basics about the AI agent. And
"let's create a training and make the flow from scratch for you to get out of this tutorial with this complete flow set up for you to be able to use. So starting our complete course, what are you going to learn? First, the basics of the agents."
"Then we will take the first steps in the N2N tool, which is a very good tool for automations,"
"integrations, but also to create AI agents from scratch. And also very important how to activate functions for your agents. And an important message, all the materials in this course will be in the description, in the link below."
"So to follow 100% with me, then download the materials here. I wanted to explain to you"
why agents are already so powerful. It's because of two reasons.
"The first one is that we can do a little thing called RAG, which is basically to take our AI"
"model and join it with other personalized data. So you can kind of train your agent to be able to access PDF data, website data, or data from a spreadsheet, any kind of personalized data from your business, you can let the agent also be able to consult this data. And besides that, we can also do function calling, or tools, which is nothing more than your agent, he can, for example, access the calendar, see events in the calendar, create events in the calendar, he can send an email, read an email, delete an email, he can go to a spreadsheet, he can access a database, so he goes to a database, he sees the data behind, or he goes there and writes new data in this database."
So your agent ends up being very powerful because you can ask him for something simple
"on WhatsApp, he goes to several other systems and does everything for you. That's why agents are already very powerful. And it is also important to make clear the difference between agents and chatbots, as agents already have a more natural language, so we can even set them to look like a real person talking, they understand any kind of natural language."
"In chatbots it's a little different, in chatbots we have both the more traditional chatbots and"
"chatbots focused a little more on AI. For example, here in Typebot, in the main chat, we make specific flows, so there are usually those buttons that you have to click on that button to follow such a flow. Here, no, who will decide the flow, the complexity, which path to follow, will be the LLM itself, which is the model itself, if you are using OpenAI, so it will respond in a much smarter way, and you can set it to be more natural."
"So that's why agents are so powerful, it's basically a new employee, not a little bot that"
"responds to the standard. So, in short, chatbots collect information and AI agents can reason, okay? And then you can ask me, Castelo, but what am I going to be able to build? To get a little more practice, you can build, for example, an AI support agent trained with your data, a sales agent, so who is selling every day on WhatsApp or any, I don't know, on Instagram, it can be an SDR agent, so he receives your leads and already sets up meetings for you, that's it, you don't need to do anything, this here is very valuable for other companies. You can make an agent that schedules medical consultations in an automatic way, you can make a barbershop scheduling agent, an adventure class scheduling agent, a delivery agent, so he receives the client's orders and already makes the order there on WhatsApp and already sends it to the client."
"So with an AI agent that has those two very powerful points, RAG and Function Calling, it"
"ends up being very powerful to create any type of agent, both for your business, but also here we promote a lot the AI manager, which offers the AI creation service for other businesses, and this is one of the professions that is exploding, but I'll leave this subject a"
little more at the end of the video for you to understand. And that way you can connect
"your AI agent on Instagram, but also mainly on WhatsApp, which is the most used app by Brazilians, so you can create a sales agent, scheduling support and connect on WhatsApp to have all the intelligence there inside WhatsApp. This is a great opportunity that is having this year."
For me to make a summary here about the architecture of an agent. So what does an agent
"mean? First of all, you have to have a model, a model of GPT, of Llama, of Cloud, of Gemini, so you have to have a model for it to be able to consume the intelligence, the LLM, which is the Large Language Model. In addition, you have to have an instruction, a base prompt."
"So here it gives you an instruction, it will be an attendant, it will follow which instructions,"
"what is his goal, what will he do, what tools will he activate, you have to give the instructions. In addition, there is memory, so short-term memory as well as long-term memory for him to remember the conversations. And there will also be the reg part here, which is for you to be able to train your agent based on PDF, text and link."
"And also the other super important factor, which is the function calling part, that you run"
"tools. So you can consult Google, consult Calendar, you can do it here in any database. So he goes to the bank, he updates, he moves the data, he can see the data."
That's why the agents are so powerful. So basically this is the architecture of the agents. And
you may have already researched that there are hundreds of tools for you to create your own agents.
But rest assured that we have already done all the studies here for you over the past
"months and years and we have already selected the best tools for you to create your agent. So in the market we have a lot of tools, we have Chatbase, we have Language Flow, Relevancy AI, we have OpenAI, where you can create the assistants, we have N2N, Udify, we have some very good Brazilian tools too, for example, Isaiah, ChatVault. So there are a lot of tools on the market."
"Of these here, certainly the best, the best costs and benefits are these three, OpenAI, N2N"
"and Udify. OpenAI, basically you create your agent and the company that grows the most in the world, is the most renowned company in IA. So the agents you create there are very robust."
"It's an easy way and you can also create scalable IA agents. N2N, we can combine two"
"worlds, which is the world of integration, automations, along with the world of creating IA agents. It is a tool that is advancing a lot in this part of creating your own agents."
And Udify is also a very good tool that has grown rapidly in recent months and it stands out
"for ease. So it's very easy to create your IA agent, you put other documents to train your agent, you activate functions. So it's very good for ease."
"And N2N and Udify, they have a big point, that they are open source. We can host. N2N is"
"not open source, but it has the possibility of hosting its service in our own hosting."
"Udify is already 100% open source, but both have the possibility of hosting on our own"
"server, which greatly reduces costs. Okay, and of these three here in our vision, N2N ends up standing out for being the best tool to create IA agents for a few reasons. The first one is that you can create very powerful automations and integrations with N2N."
"So N2N was born for that, for you to create very advanced, specialized automations. And"
"then they created an integration with IA for you to create your own agents. So we can centralize everything in a single tool, which ends up being very practical and powerful."
"In addition, there is this new node, this new point of N2N's flow, which emerged some time"
"ago. They already made it much better. In the beginning it was a little immature, it wasn't working very well, but now it already has a node that integrates with N2N, which is nothing more for you to build your IA agents."
"This makes it very easy, because with these possibilities we can make powerful IA agents. So"
"here we will be able to do both the reg part, both the functions part, and also do, for example, more complex projects, such as multi-agents. And all of this, no code, okay? Everything I say here is always no code."
"That's why it's very powerful. And besides that, it has the possibility to host our N2N system,"
"our technology, in our own hosting, which reduces costs a lot. This makes it totally in the game."
"So, bringing a spoiler, we have this node here, which is the node of the IA agent, and then"
"we can do what I had talked about, the fundamentals of the agents. We connect our model, we can also put memory, and we can put functions. Here, for example, is a function to create events in the agenda."
"This is what we will learn step by step. And besides that, we can connect the N2N with"
"several models, okay? For example, with GPT, with LLAMA, with Cloud, with Gemini. So, we have this flexibility, which ends up being excellent for joining the project courses as well."
"And an interesting point that I brought here is that the N2N is growing a lot, really a lot. So,"
"this year, for those who are working with N2N, it's starting to open up a lot of opportunities, because it's a tool, look. Look at the interest in the word N2N for a while."
"So, it exploded here in the last few months, because people are seeing that the tool is really,"
"it is very powerful, and it brings a lot of power there for you to offer agent creation services. So, now we are well on the curve that is growing. So, there are a lot of opportunities and a lot of people looking for developers who create people already using the N2N tool."
"So, I recommend you learn, to be able to advance well in N2N, that you will have many"
"opportunities and it will open many doors for you. Here is a golden tip for your career, for you to start making money with automation tools, no-code tools, and agent creation tools. And now, to talk a little bit about the architecture of our project."
"Let's go here quickly, because in a little while we're going to practice, okay? Calm down,"
"we're already going to practice. First, we're going to have the front-end. The front-end is"
"just the interface of your project, where you visualize, where the user interacts with your"
project.
"And in the front-end here, we're going to use Telegram. But this tool is very good, because"
"we will be able to send text, audio, it will be very practical. And we could, for example, use WhatsApp, but WhatsApp is a little more complex, because we have to use a WhatsApp API."
"And now, for us to learn well, let's learn with Telegram, and then we'll learn with WhatsApp,"
"okay? To automate integrations, we're going to use N2N, which is a top-of-the-line tool to create automations and AGI. In addition, our AGI will already have the N2N node, and here we will also integrate with Calendar, the service that we will integrate. And the model that we will use from LLM, remember that you always have to have the sum, is the GPT model from OpenAI."
"So, look how cool, the design of our architecture, our AGI project, that you will learn here"
"with me, step by step. So, let's get started. Let's go with me here on the N2N website, for us to do the practical part of this AGI Super Agents course in here."
"Let's go. I'm already here on the N2N website, let's create our first agent in practice. Then, if"
"you want, you can search a little more, explore a little here on the site, explain correctly what the tool is, how to create the AGI, that's exactly what we're going to do, in a very practical and fast way, for us to be able to create our agents."
"In addition, we can put code, if necessary, we can move some information here, and there"
"are more than 400 integrations available with tools and platforms on the internet. Okay? Then, if you want to take a look here, now it's not really the goal, what we're going to do now, let's come here to the pricing, for you to understand how the price of N2N works. So, this site here, the company N2N, we can use N2N through the platform itself, then we would have to pay a monthly fee."
"And this monthly fee here, has a starter plan, which is R$ 125 per month, has a PRO plan,"
"which is R$ 333, and has an ENTERPRISE plan, okay? Here you can see what's on each plan, and here, there's a message saying Hosted by N2N, what does it mean? It means that N2N will be hosted in the company N2N itself, okay? Here, the plans, they are very... For me, the values are very accessible by the value that the tool brings, but we also have the possibility to take N2N's technology and put it in our own hosting. This way, we will save a lot, that's why N2N is so powerful. It has this possibility of using it here, but we can also use it in our own hosting."
"This is a theme for a future class, okay? Now, we're going to make a free account here,"
"because you can do a 14-day free trial with some OpenAI credits. So, let's start with the free account to learn, okay? So, follow me and let's make a new free account here, okay? So, it's important that you do it here so you can have access to some credits that they will give here later. Later on, when you start to understand about the agents, about the integrations, you take N2N and you can put it in your own hosting."
"We have tutorials about this too. So, let's go! I'm going to come here in Start Free Trial and"
"make your account and let's go to the N2N panel, okay? I'm going to skip to this part to cut this part of the video. So, I'm already here in my N2N panel, okay? So, here is where the"
"workflows will be, which is nothing more than our automations, okay? So, here, we will be"
able to create workflows later.
"Here, we will be able to put our credentials, okay? This is my credential here, it's already"
"enabled because it's a credit that I got, okay? I'll show you how to do it. Don't worry. And here are our executions, okay? We can see here."
"So, in a little while, we'll go a little deeper. Here on the sidebar, without much follow-up, we"
can also put our projects. I'm just going to change a little detail here that I like to make it a little more visual.
I'm going to come here in Settings and I'm going to come here and I'm going to put the Light
"Theme, okay? Just to stay in the Light version here because I think it's clearer here to be able to go through the whole tutorial, okay? But if you're from Dark Mode, you can leave it there in Dark and continue the tutorial, which is the same, okay? So, okay. Let's go straight to practice. Then we can explore a little more here and let's come here, look, Start From Scratch, okay? So, look how cool."
"This is the panel that we're going to do all the automations and our Agent, okay? Here, if"
"you come up here, you'll see that I, in this case, have 8 free days because I made my account a few days ago, okay? So, we can use it a lot, learn and test the tool to then need to pay for it, okay? So, rest assured that you don't need to pay for the tool. Okay, here we can create our first step of automation, right? So, if I click here, look, there are several options, right?"
"There are trigger options, which are, for example, when I press a button, my automation will occur. Or, for example, when the email arrives, the automation will occur."
"When a file is placed on the drive, the automation will occur. So, here, N820 works a lot"
"with triggers, okay? We're not going to see a lot of triggers now, or to be able to set a time, or what is an ambihook. Here are several and several options, okay? We're going to focus on the Agent A part because we want to be well focused here in our Agent A course, okay?"
Then we'll have a course just for N820.
"And then you can learn a little more about automations, integrations and other types of"
"nodes here at N820. I'm going to put it here, write Agent, okay? And then there will be a part here called AI Agent. Then you can click, okay? So, here, we're going to configure our Agent A. It will open this Agent A configuration."
"We'll leave it as it is, okay? It will be a tool Agent A. It will be added by the chat itself. We're"
"going to show an automatic chat here. Here's the prompt, right? Which will be the user's own question."
"And here are a few more options. But you can close this now, look. Come here and click"
Back to Canvas.
Show! So here our Agent A is ready. So what does it mean? That way we can test it. We're
going to have a chat here.
"This chat, just come here on the orange button, look. In chat. And here we'll be able to test"
"it, okay? For now, it's not working because we haven't configured it."
"But look how cool our Agent is, look how easy. We can have an agent model here, okay? So"
"the model will be the OpenAI model. I don't know, the Llama model."
Gemini model. Here we're going to put the model. Here's the memory.
For us to be able to remember the context of the conversation. And long-term memory.
Then we'll put the memory.
"And Tools are the tools. Which is the great power here of Agent A. We can connect email,"
calendar tools. Connect to a spreadsheet.
Connect to a database. For him to read databases. For him to write in a database.
"So that's what we're going to explore here, okay? So let's test it. First, I'm going to come"
here in my model. Let's configure the model.
Remember that I said the power of Agent A. We have the part of the model. And he can do
"both the reg part and the functions part. First, let's start here with the model."
"Here, there's the Anthropic model. Azure. There's Gemini."
"And there's OpenAI here, okay? Let's use OpenAI, which is a more structured and"
"professional model. Okay. Here, if you made your account from scratch."
You'll have a little button here. To get free N2N credits for OpenAI. So N2N releases free
credits.
"For you to be able to use there. And you don't have to pay, right? If you don't have these"
"credits, you'll have to pay. Five dollars, a little money there for OpenAI."
"It will last a long time, okay? For us to be able to use OpenAI's API. If you created your free"
account here with me. Just click on your button here.
"And ask for your credits, okay? If you already have an N2N account. It's already hosted. Then"
I'll leave a step-by-step later.
The materials and description. Just how you can connect. OpenAI's API key.
"With your N2N, okay? If you don't have it, just click here. And connect, look. N2N Free"
"OpenAI Credits, okay? And then we can follow."
"So, let's go. We will use the credential that is already ready here. And we will use the"
GPT4OMINI model.
"In this case, I can only use this model here. Because this free account only allows you to use"
this model. If you connect your own platform to OpenAI.
"Then you can use other models, okay? That's it here. We don't need to do anything else. We"
connect our model.
"And it's all right. So it will already have an input, right? Beauty. Here's our model."
"All right. OpenAI Chat Model. Now, let's put a memory."
"For our agent to be able to remember, right? Otherwise, he will be a very stupid agent."
"Here, we have a memory called Window Buffer Memory. Which is the ISIST."
"It is a memory of the N2N itself to store the data. Later on, to make it more professional and"
"structured. It's better to use Postgres or Redis memory, for example."
"Later on, I'll teach you how to do this in other tutorials, okay? Now we will follow here with"
the N2N's own memory. Beauty. And here everything is already set.
It's already connected. It's already pulling the ID here. And it will basically take each
message from the conversation.
And it will save it in a memory. So you can use it in the conversation itself. Too cool.
"I already put an agent with memory, right? And an interesting point that we can continue"
here. Is to come to our AI Agent. Let's click.
Here in properties. We can come here to System Message. Beauty.
You can click there. And here we will put the prompt. Which is the instructions of our agent.
"So let's put an agent here. You are an attendant. How can he give a personality to him,"
right? I'll put it here.
Without much patience. And addicted to coffee. You treat users badly.
And is always sleepy. Tired. And makes bad vibes jokes.
I don't know. Put the instructions there if you want. Just for us to test here.
It's our instruction. Our app. All right here.
"I'll save. To save this flow. If you want, you can rename here."
I'll put it here. My AI Agent. Beauty.
Now beauty. I can come here in the chat. For us to test.
So I came here. Oops. All right.
Let's see. So it will run. It ran.
He said. Everything is fine. Of course.
I'm just here for an hour. Without looking at a coffee. And you.
How are you? If we don't have the end of a monologue about life. It's better to go straight
to the point. He's a little stressed.
Our attendant. And look how cool. Here is the chat.
So we have an edit. Our chat. We can even delete it.
To clean. And here. What did he do? He ran here.
Our model. So he went to the PNA. And sent our model.
I brought an answer. And here too. We can see the log.
"It's very important to see the log. We can see what's going on here. Here, for example."
At the time of memory. He added. The memory message.
Oops. All right. And the prompt.
Our memory list. That way. The agent can remember.
So I say. My name. It's Mateus.
"I'll tell him. It will run. Cool, Mateus."
Now that we have. The most exciting part of the day. What do you want? If I'm a journalist.
Of things. I can matter. I'm sorry.
I'm not a coffee machine. Or am I? I don't really understand you. The coffee footprint.
I'll say. What is. My name? What's my name? It will run again.
"He will say. I don't know, Mateus. I hope you have noted."
I may not be interested in your life. But at least I have good memory. Cool.
Let's take his memory. I'll come here. I'll exclude.
Just to test. Let's take his memory. Save.
I'll clean. I cleaned the memories. I'll come here.
"Hi. My name is Mateus. Hi, Mateus."
How good. Plus the name in the line. What do you want? Please.
Do it fast. Because I'm in need of coffee. What is.
My name? If I had to guess. I would say that your name is. Tired of waiting for an answer.
So he doesn't remember the name. Because there is no memory. That's why it's so
important.
We put. A memory. Cool.
I'll come here. And I'll put. The memory.
Again. So look how cool. We already have.
Our first agent. And now. We can come here.
And start. Making the part. Of functions.
Let's go then. Make functions. So now.
We're going to talk about. Tools. Which is the real power.
Of our agents. With tools. Or tools.
Our agent will be able to. Connect with any other tool. On the internet.
With Gmail. With Calendar. Or with your own system.
Or for example. He can go to the database. And bring data.
From your database. Or he can go there. In your database.
And write new data. So he creates data. For you.
And then the possibilities. Are infinite. But let's go from scratch here.
For us to see how it works. This part of tools. Beauty.
I'm here in my agent. Already. And I'll come here.
And more. Okay. So look how much.
That we can do. We can call. Other flows.
From n8n. We can call. A code.
Let's make a call. API. To connect.
With any other system. Here's the part. Database.
Vector. Okay. This here.
I'll leave you a little further on. Which is the databases. When you work.
With a GA project. And here. Are all other tools.
That n8n. It already integrates. Natively.
But you can integrate. Basically. With something on the internet.
And if that other system. He has an API documentation. Okay.
So. There's a word table. There's a base row.
There's the calculator. There's Gmail. Calendar.
There's Google Docs. Drive. Schedule.
So. All the tools you have here. We can.
So much. Go there. And read these tools.
Interact with them. Create new data. Get data.
Update. And come back. And show the answer.
From our agent. Okay. There's not much here.
There's Notion. There's PushGrid. There's Redis.
Dude. There's a basic soup. That we like a lot.
So. To test. We'll start first here.
To start. Let's come here. Let's get the calculator.
Okay. A nice example. You don't need to configure anything.
It's already integrated. And we're also going to come here. In Tool.
Oops. I accidentally disconnected. Connect again.
And let's also connect here. Wikipedia. Beauty.
Let's connect Wikipedia. Now. We need to come here.
In the agent's instructions. And talk. When he should.
Activate these tools. Okay. So.
I'm going to come here. In the prompt. I'll talk like this.
It's you. Should. Activate.
Your. Calculator. Whenever.
The. User. Ask.
Something. About. Mathematics.
And Calculus. So. We explain to him.
Very easy. You. Should.
Activate. Your. Calculator.
Wikipedia. Whenever. User.
Ask. Something. About.
Mathematics. And Calculus. We explain to him.
Very easy. You. Should.
Activate. Your. Whenever.
Mathematics. And Calculus. You.
Should. Activate. Your.
Should. Activate. Your.
Calculator. You. Should.
Activate. Your. Calculator.
You. Should. You.
Should. Your. Calculator.
You. Should. Activate.
Calculator. You. Activate.
Your. Calculator. You.
Should. Your. Calculator.
You. Should. Activate.
Your. Calculator. You.
Should. You. Should.
Calculator. Calculator. You.
Should. Activate. Your.
Calculator. You. Should.
Activate. Your. Calculator.
You. Activate. Calculator.
Should. Your. Calculator.
You. Your. Calculator.
"You. In relation to N2N, hosted in the N2N itself, you just need to connect your Gmail to"
"your Google account, ok? If not, if you are hosted on another platform, you will have to follow some other steps, a little more annoying, but it's only 5 minutes, then you'll have to do this integration, ok?"
This file is longer than 30 minutes.
Go Unlimited at TurboScribe.ai to transcribe files up to 10 hours long.
